<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CSS on Hello. I&#39;m Dean Clatworthy</title>
    <link>https://deanclatworthy.com/categories/css.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in CSS on Hello. I&#39;m Dean Clatworthy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://deanclatworthy.com/categories/css/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Web fonts not loading in Firefox</title>
      <link>https://deanclatworthy.com/2013/06/web-fonts-not-loading-in-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deanclatworthy.com/2013/06/web-fonts-not-loading-in-firefox/</guid>
      <description>I encountered a peculiar issue today regarding web fonts on firefox. On all browsers except Firefox the web fonts were loading correctly. I found multiple references suggesting that Firefox was picky with using quotes when referencing where the font file is hosted. However my findings were more interesting:
Firefox does not support embedding webfont files from a different domain
The good news is the fix is simple. Simply send the following header:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Photoshop PSD template for Twitter Bootstrap&#39;s responsive grid</title>
      <link>https://deanclatworthy.com/2013/01/a-photoshop-psd-template-for-twitter-bootstraps-responsive-grid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deanclatworthy.com/2013/01/a-photoshop-psd-template-for-twitter-bootstraps-responsive-grid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit:&lt;/strong&gt; This article is a little out-dated now, as Bootstrap is on version 3 featuring a completely different and fluid grid. It&amp;rsquo;s still applicable if you are working with the older Bootstrap (up to version 2.3.2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges I have faced when doing my front-end work is trying to communicate to designers who have not done too much responsive work with Bootstrap, how the grid works. It&amp;rsquo;s not as simple as telling someone to make a 968px wide layout anymore. One has to consider differing breakpoints. One of the interesting things about Twitter bootstrap is that in its &lt;a href=&#34;http://getbootstrap.com/2.3.2/scaffolding.html#responsive&#34;&gt;scaffolding guide&lt;/a&gt; it talks about breakpoints at 1200px and 980px but you don&amp;rsquo;t actually have that much width to work with. There is always a margin applied to the left of the layout resulting in only 1170px of available space on a 1200px grid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS grid layouts using HashGrid</title>
      <link>https://deanclatworthy.com/2010/04/css-grid-layouts-using-hashgrid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deanclatworthy.com/2010/04/css-grid-layouts-using-hashgrid/</guid>
      <description>Just a heads up to anyone who&amp;rsquo;s planning on designing their next project using a grid. The folks over at Analog have created a nifty little tool called Hashgrid to overlay a grid over your web page like so:

Installation is pretty simple but I ran into a couple of minor issues which hopefully can be remedied in a future version:
 The negative margin in the example is half the width of your grid, and whilst that&amp;rsquo;s probably obvious it may be worth adding a comment in the CSS on hashgrid.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
