<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello. I&#39;m Dean Clatworthy</title>
    <link>https://deanclatworthy.com/categories/bootstrap.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hello. I&#39;m Dean Clatworthy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://deanclatworthy.com/categories/bootstrap.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A Photoshop PSD template for Twitter Bootstrap&#39;s responsive grid</title>
      <link>https://deanclatworthy.com/2013/01/a-photoshop-psd-template-for-twitter-bootstraps-responsive-grid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deanclatworthy.com/2013/01/a-photoshop-psd-template-for-twitter-bootstraps-responsive-grid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit:&lt;/strong&gt; This article is a little out-dated now, as Bootstrap is on version 3 featuring a completely different and fluid grid. It&amp;rsquo;s still applicable if you are working with the older Bootstrap (up to version 2.3.2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges I have faced when doing my front-end work is trying to communicate to designers who have not done too much responsive work with Bootstrap, how the grid works. It&amp;rsquo;s not as simple as telling someone to make a 968px wide layout anymore. One has to consider differing breakpoints. One of the interesting things about Twitter bootstrap is that in its &lt;a href=&#34;http://getbootstrap.com/2.3.2/scaffolding.html#responsive&#34;&gt;scaffolding guide&lt;/a&gt; it talks about breakpoints at 1200px and 980px but you don&amp;rsquo;t actually have that much width to work with. There is always a margin applied to the left of the layout resulting in only 1170px of available space on a 1200px grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, one has to then consider the margins in between the columns on the grid. Rather than leave this to interpretation I created this PSD template. You can just rip out the layers from it and put it on top of your existing design, or use it as a starting point to any of your designs which will utilise Bootstrap. It overlays a translucent grid for the top 3 bootstrap breakpoints: 1200px, 980px and 768px.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deanclatworthy.com/2013/01/a-photoshop-psd-template-for-twitter-bootstraps-responsive-grid/bootstrap-guide/&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-288&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-large wp-image-288&#34; alt=&#34;Bootstrap-Guide&#34; src=&#34;//deanclatworthy.com/img/uploads/2013/01/Bootstrap-Guide-1024x682.png&#34; width=&#34;625&#34; height=&#34;416&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can utilise any of the space in green, but do not place anything on the leftmost or rightmost red areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I should, at this point, also stress that if you can/want to use the fluid layout of Bootstrap then this template will obviously be of no use to you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download the template by clicking here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/Z1jp00&#34;&gt;Download Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>